now that I'm satisfied with the content
structure and layout of the presentation
it's time to start thinking about adding
some additional effects that will
enhance the meaning and appearance when
presented to an audience the two tools
that I'm going to look at are
transitions and animations the first
thing the transitions is quite simply
how one slide will transition into
another slate so at the moment when I
click on slideshow and clear the
slideshow from the beginning the first
light appears instantly and then as I
click each slide then appears instantly
so if I press the exit button and go
back to my presentation
if I select slide 1 and then I go to the
transitions tab and select that as you
can see along the top that are a range
of transition effects that can be
applied and just as an example I'm going
to select split so that is the effect
that will be applied to that slate you
can select different transitions for
different slides but if you are
presenting this to a professional
audience I would recommend maintaining
consistency within the slide so the
transition should be the same and there
is an easy way of doing ups or a selects
later on again I know that split has
been applied as slate 1 so if I move
over to the right and select the apply
to wall button that has been applied
that same transition effect to all of
the slates so if I go to slideshow and
play that now every time I click each
label transition in with the effect that
I have applied so once I'm happy with
the transitions I can then think about
adding some animation effects so
animation effects can be applied to
different sections and elements within
your presentation so to access the
animations I need to click on the
animations tab and as you can see along
the top all of the animation effects are
currently grayed out there will not
become active until I select an element
within a slate to honor me it but as
soon as I click into the text box there
they all become active and again as with
the transitions you
can click each one and it will apply
that effect to the selected element and
when you're satisfied with the one that
you wish to use and I'm going to select
GRU and turn by that element there and
then I'm going to apply some animation
to the two images and the other element
of text so I'll highlight the first
image and I want to select feared for
that one
then I will highlight the second image
and I will select float in for that one
and finally I will select the seals
report and I want to stick with the GRU
in tune so that is consistent with the
text at the top so now I've applied for
some animation effects to that slate so
if I played that now I go to slideshow
selected from beginning it transitions
in and if I click the first element
appears I click again the second element
and again and again
well actually again the only thing I
have set up on the other sites are
transitions so there's no animation
effects yet so we'll just transition
through each of those so once I'm
satisfied with the animations on slide
one I can then go on to slay two three
four and five and add animation effects
to doors there are other some other
features within the animations that you
can use to delay and enhance the
animations which will be covered in
session 6